A Guide to the Rockefeller Family and Associates (Room 5600), General Files, 1987-1991, RG 39 FA1505
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Rockefeller Family and Associates (Room 5600), General Files, 1987-1991; 39
  - Welfare, 1987-1991; 35
    - Day Nurseries - Children's Storefront (Box 576, Folder 3)
    - Day Nurseries - Children's Storefront - Cousins (Box 579, Folder 18)
    - Family Counseling (Box 576, Folder 4)
    - Family Counseling - Cousins and Fifth Generation (Box 579, Folder 19-20)
    - Family Counseling - Family Service of Westchester (Box 576, Folder 5)
    - Family Counseling - Family Service of Westchester - Cousins (Box 567, Folder 5)
    - Handicapped - A-Z (Box 577, Folder 1-4)
    - Handicapped - A-Z - Cousins (Box 567, Folder 6-9)
    - Handicapped - International Center for Disabled (ICD) (Box 577, Folder 5)
    - Handicapped - New York League for the Hard of Hearing (Box 578, Folder 1)
    - Homes - A-Z (Box 578, Folder 2-3)
    - Homes - A-O - Cousins and Fifth Generation (Box 567, Folder 10-11)
    - Homes - P-Z - Cousins and Fifth Generation (Box 580, Folder 1-2)
    - (American) Indians/Native Americans - A-Z (Box 578, Folder 4)
    - (American) Indians/Native Americans - A-Z - Cousins (Box 580, Folder 3)
    - (American) Indians/Native Americans - Indian Law Resource Center (Box 578, Folder 5)
    - (American) Indians/Native Americans - Indian Law Resource Center - Cousins (Box 580, Folder 4)
    - (American) Indians/Native Americans - Institute for Resource Management (Box 580, Folder 5)
    - (American) Indians/Native Americans - Redsun Institute (Box 581, Folder 1-2)
    - (American) Indians/Native Americans - Seventh Generation Fund for Indian Development, Inc. (Box 581, Folder 3)
    - (American) Indians/Native Americans - Seventh Generation Fund for Indian Development, Inc. - Cousins (Box 580, Folder 6)
    - Legal - A-Z (Box 581, Folder 4)
    - Legal - A-Z - Cousins (Box 580, Folder 7)
    - Legal - Pacific Legal Foundation (Box 581, Folder 5)
    - Musicians - A-Z (Box 582, Folder 1)
    - Orphans - A-Z (Box 582, Folder 2)
    - Orphans - A-Z - Cousins (Box 580, Folder 8)
    - United Funds - A-Z (Box 582, Folder 3-4)
    - United Funds - A-Z - Cousins (Box 580, Folder 9)
    - United Way of Tri-State (Box 582, Folder 4)
    - United Funds - United Way of the Tri-State - Cousins (Box 580, Folder 10)
  - Women, 1987-1991; 36
    - Women - A-Z (Box 583, Folder 1)
    - Women - A-Z - Cousins (Box 586, Folder 1)
    - Catalyst (Box 582, Folder 6)
    - Ms. Foundation for Women (Box 583, Folder 2)
    - Ms. Foundation for Women, Inc. - Cousins (Box 586, Folder 2)
    - NOW Legal Defense and Education Fund (Box 583, Folder 3)
    - National Women's Health Network (Box 583, Folder 4)
    - National Women's Health Network - Cousins (Box 586, Folder 3)
  - Youth, 1987-1991; 37
    - Youth - A-D (Box 584, Folder 1-4)
    - Youth - E-Z (Box 585, Folder 1-3)
    - Youth - A-Z - Cousins (Box 586, Folder 4-9)
    - Boys Club of New York (Box 585, Folder 4)
    - Boys Club of St. Croix (Box 587, Folder 1)
    - Boys Clubs of America (Box 587, Folder 2)
    - Boy Scouts of America (Box 587, Folder 3)
    - Boy Scouts of America - Cousins (Box 586, Folder 10)
    - Children's Aid Society (Box 587, Folder 4)
    - Children's Aid Society - Cousins and Fifth Generation (Box 586, Folder 11-12)
    - Covenant House (Box 588, Folder 1-2)
    - Covenant House - Fifth Generation (Box 586, Folder 13)
    - Girl Scouts of America (Box 588, Folder 3)
    - Graham-Windham Services to Families and Children (Box 588, Folder 4)
    - Infant Formula Action Coalition (INFACT) (Box 586, Folder 14)
    - Junior Achievement (Box 589, Folder 1)
    - Junior Achievement, Inc. - Cousins (Box 586, Folder 15)
    - Hugh O'Brian Youth Foundation (Box 589, Folder 2)
    - Police Athletic League, Inc. (Box 589, Folder 3)
    - Chi Chi Rodriguez Youth Foundation (Box 589, Folder 4)
    - Save the Children Foundation (Box 589, Folder 5)
    - Save the Children Federation - Cousins (Box 586, Folder 16)
    - Vocational Foundation (Box 590, Folder 1)
    - YMCA - A-Z (Box 590, Folder 2)
    - YMCA - A-Z - Cousins (Box 593, Folder 1)
    - YMCA - Greater New York (Box 590, Folder 3)
    - YMCA - Greater New York - Cousins and Fifth Generation (Box 593, Folder 2-3)
    - YWCA (Box 590, Folder 4)
    - YWCA - Hawaii Island YWCA (Box 590, Folder 5)
    - YWCA - National Board (Box 591, Folder 1)
    - YWCA - National Board - Contributions (Box 591, Folder 2)
    - YMCA - National Board - Contributions - Cousins (Box 593, Folder 4)
    - YWCA - New York City (Box 591, Folder 3)
    - YWCA - New York City - Cousins (Box 593, Folder 5)
    - YWCA - New York City - Printed Matter (Box 591, Folder 4)
    - The Youth Project (Box 593, Folder 6)
    - Camps (Box 591, Folder 5)
    - Camps - Cousins (Box 593, Folder 7)
    - Camps - The Fresh Air Fund (Box 592, Folder 1)
    - Camps - The Fresh Air Fund - Cousins (Box 593, Folder 8)
    - Homes (Box 592, Folder 2)
    - Homes - Cousins and Fifth Generation (Box 593, Folder 9-10)
  - Y-Z, 1987-1991; 38
    - Y - Miscellaneous (Box 583, Folder 5)
    - Z - Miscellaneous (Box 592, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Ephemera, 1940-1988; 39
    - Basic Needs Corporate Records and Seal (Box 594, Folder 1)
    - State of New York - Legislative Resolution 483, Mourning the death of John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1978 July 17 (Box 594, Folder 2)
    - California Historical Society - Education, Health and Welfare Award to John D. Rockefeller Jr., 1988 June 19 (Box 594, Folder 3)
    - Fordham University - A Century of Culture (Box 594, Folder 4)
    - The Arts and American Business: A Statement to Corporations, by John D. Rockefeller 3rd (Box 594, Folder 5)
    - Spelman College - Spelman Mesenger, 1951 (Box 594, Folder 6)
    - Vesmar, 1949 (Box 594, Folder 7)
    - Virgin Island - Heritage Series Number One - The Virgins: A Descriptive and Historical Profile (Box 594, Folder 8)
    - Order of the Rising Sun 5th Class, Presented by the Emperor of Japan (Box 594, Folder 9)
      Scope and Contents
      David Rockefeller noted that this was presented to either his father John D. Rockefeller Jr, or his mother, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller.
    - Order of St. Anna,, Cross and Star with Diamonds (Orders given to Paul Ehrlich) - Case Only (Box 594, Folder 10)
      Case only.
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund - Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation - Resolution (Box 595)
    - Investment funds, circa 1940-1958 (Box 596)
  - Audiovisual Materials, 1987-1991; 40
    Sound recordings; Moving Images
    - Arts - National Committee for the Vatican Judaica Exhibition - "A Visual Testimony: Judaica from the Vatican Library", 1987 May; VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 11955)
      Access copy currently unavailable. Please see a RAC archivist for further assistance.
    - Arts - Japan Art Association - "The Establishment of Praemium Imperiale", VHS, NTSC (Box 1, Tape AV 11956)
    - Arts - Libraries - Library of Congress - "Memory and Imagination: New Pathways to the Library of Congress", VHS; 58 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 11957)
      Access copy currently unavailable. Please see a RAC archvist for further instruction.
    - Arts - Museums - Smithsonian Institution - J. Carter Brown Speech, National Press Club Luncheon, 1989 June 20; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15316)
      Part 1: Introduction/Speech (28 minutes). Part 2: Question and Answer (19 minutes)
    - Arts - Music - Carnegie Hall Society - Dalrymple Productions - "Carnegie Hall's Restoration - The 28 Week Miracle", 1988 June 1; VHS; 28 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 11958)
      Access copy currently unavailable. Please see a RAC archvist for further assistance.
      Television documentary which tells tells the story of the music hall's restoration. Aired on Channel 13 (PBS-TV) on June 9, 1988 at 9:30 PM.
    - Civic - "The Paris Liberty Flame", International Herald Tribune, 1989 May 10; VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 11960)
      Access copy currently unavailable. Please see a Archivist for further assistance.
    - Civic - Starserve: A Project of the Kraft General Foods Foundation - "Interview with Mike Love", 1991 April 6; VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 11961)
      Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
      WABC-TV News at 7:30, Starserve Santa Monica, CA
    - Raleigh Tavern Society - "A Tradition of Philanthropy", VHS; 12 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 11962)
      Access copy currently unavailable. Contact a RAC archivist for further assistance.
    - National Geographic Television, "Survivors of Skeleton Coast", VHS; 57 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 11963)
    - Education - Colleges - United Negro College Fund - "United Negro College Fund Presents Campaign 2000: An Investment in America's Future", 1990; VHS; 11 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 11964)
      New York Television, Inc. (NYTV)
    - Education - Colleges - University of Louisville - Joel Elkes - "Arts in Medicine Program, Division of Attitudinal and Behavioral Medicine, University of Louisville, KY, VHS; 23 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 11965)
    - Education - Colleges - University of Louisville - Health Awareness Workshop, VHS; 19 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 11966)
    - Education - Foundations - George C. Marshall Foundation - "George C. Marshall - American Leadership", VHS; 12 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 11967)
    - American Soviet Youth Orchestra - July 19, Bolshoi Hall, Moscow State Conservatory (Global American Television), VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 11968)
    - Chico Mendes: Voice of the Amazon, VHS; 56 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 11969)
    - Up With People: 25th Anniversary Highlights, VHS; 11 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 11970)
    - Medicine - Institute for Humanistic Science - "Biobehavioral Systems", VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 11971)
    - Medicine - Juvenile Diabetes Foundation - "The Only Remedy Is A Cure", VHS; 7 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 11972)
    - New York Republican State Committee, 1989 October 13; VHS; 6 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 11973)
    - "An Introduction to Contemplative Visions", Winters Productions, 1990 November 30 (date stamp); VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 11974)
    - Woodstock Foundation - Calvin Coolidge Memorial Foundation - "Coolidge Preview" - Archival Film Samples, VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 11975)
    - Winrock International Conference Center, 1989 October 12; VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 11976)
    - Valley Ranch New Room Construction, VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 11977)
      To: Mrs. Jean Branscombe. From: Dick Long.
    - Covenant House - Awards Dinner, VHS; 12 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 11978)
    - Youth - Homes - WPIX - "The Best Talk in Town", The Children's Village, 1988 Spring; VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 11979)